Yoonsie Kim

571-551-9067 Arlington, VA yoonsie.kim@gmail.com <u>linkedin.com/in/yoonsiekim</u>

Former web developer turned product manager with 5 years of product experience leading customer discovery interviews, increasing customer acquisition, and driving revenue for products ranging from content creation and audio/video conferencing to onboarding and automation software.

Experience

Product Manager Remote 2021 - Present Class

As one of the first product hires, led a team of 30+ engineers and designers to build the core products of a B2B SaaS EdTech global startup (\$100M Series B) to increase customers 3x

- Initiated discovery sessions, identified 12 piloting prospects experiencing issues managing tools during screenshare, launched an enhancement resulting in 20% increase in revenue
- Identified 30% of customer contact sourced from a request for a differentiating proctor feature, aligned cross-functionally with sales, customer success, marketing, engineering, and design to scope and ship a first iteration, decreasing customer contact 30%
- Launched a whiteboard feature to close market gap leading to 10% revenue increase
- Defined product strategy with stakeholders from 0 to 1; define and own product roadmaps, including one for the corporate vertical comprising Fortune 500 customers
- Streamlined creation and management of user stories, cutting costs 75%

Senior Product Consultant / Product Owner

Remote Attain (now Maximus) 2020 - 2021

Owned the full product lifecycle for a financial services client to build a cloud-based case management application from scratch to replace a costly manual documentation process

- Led Agile team of 12 engineers, designers, business analysts to launch a document review workflow, decreasing time-to-review by 80% and leading to renewals for a \$115M contract
- Leveraged wireframes and proof of concepts to test hypotheses and drive priorities, including a Outlook email integration which would decrease scheduling time 95%

Senior Product Consultant / Product Owner

Macedon Technologies

Reston, VA 2017 - 2020

Built B2B software products for customers and received a CEO-recognized award

- Interviewed customers and launched product iteration improving a key metric by 95% and reducing the time to log opportunities and prospects for a custom CRM application
- Leveraged SQL to identify a 5 minute workflow for a project creation process, led interviews and prototyped a solution that reduced the time to 15 seconds or less
- Led cross-functional team of 20+, identified cross-stream dependencies, and strategically prioritized work to decrease dependencies and reduce a 3 hour launch time to 30 minutes

Skills

- Product strategy, roadmapping, data analysis, competitive analysis, prioritization, wireframing, prototyping, Figma, Balsamiq
- Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, python, SQL, Atlassian JIRA, Confluence

Education

University of Rochester, B.A. Digital Media Studies-Computer Science, 3.8/4.0 | Rochester, NY